agora.org 2014-11-22

# Privacy Policy | Agora Cyber Charter School

###  **Understand Our Policy Regarding Your Input on Agora's Website**

K¹²'s unique program combines online technology with traditional content and the world's best teaching methods. We, K¹², have established this privacy policy to let you know how we collect and use information that we may gather from you on this website, K12.com, and the websites of our affiliated schools ("affiliates") (these websites collectively are referenced as "Sites" in this policy; all of the Sites are owned and operated by K¹²). This privacy policy discloses how we collect, use, share, and protect information gathered about you on our Sites.

This policy only applies to information that we collect through our Sites and does not apply to information that we may collect from you in other ways (for example, this policy does not apply to information that you may provide to us over the phone, by fax or through conventional mail). In addition, please note that this policy does not apply to your children's educational records—those records are protected by the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act and we at K¹² are committed to compliance with that law.

  * Non-Personal and Aggregated Information Collected Automatically
  * Use of Cookies
  * Personal Information You Provide
  * Personal Information Provided by Parents About Children
  * Message Boards and Chats
  * Links
  * Our Commitment to Data Security
  * Changes in Corporate Structure
  * Changes to the Privacy Policy
  * Participation in the U.S.-E.U. and U.S.-Switzerland Safe Harbor Programs
  * K¹² Customer and Employee Safe Harbor Privacy Policy

**Non-Personal and Aggregated Information Collected Automatically**

Each time you visit our website, we log non-personal information, such as your IP address, domain name, the name of the Web page from which you entered our website, which pages you visit on our website, and how much time you spend on each page. We use this information to monitor and improve our website and for internal analysis. In particular, we use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the website, and gather information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information.

**Use of Cookies**

Our website uses "cookies" to help personalize your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is anonymously placed on your hard disk by a web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you. We use cookies to keep track of how you are using the Sites, to tailor Web content to your interests. If you have registered your children for a K¹² virtual program, cookies will speed up and ease your access to the OLS, as defined below, and navigation around the OLS. K¹² cookies do not contain personal information about the parent(s) or children enrolled in K¹² virtual program.

We will not share or sell non-aggregated information contained within cookies to any third party.

You also have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of our Sites or have some of our services on the Sites function properly. If you choose to decline cookies, you will not be able to access the OLS or have your children enrolled in a virtual program.

**Personal Information You Provide**

You can use portions of our Sites without divulging any personal information including your e-mail address. Our Sites do not collect personal information about individuals except when such individuals specifically provide such information on a voluntary basis, for example when you request a catalog, request additional information by contacting us, post a message to a message board, request help, or access and add to or change the information on your account information page on the OLS. When you register your children for a K¹² virtual program or participate in a K¹² virtual program through an affiliate or local school we may collect information regarding you and your children but all such information will be collected over the phone, by fax or through conventional mail. Once you have registered your children for a K¹² virtual program, there is an online service for all such programs (collectively the "OLS"). There will be a personal information page on the OLS that contains some or all of your personal information. You may also be assigned a Member ID and password and may create, at your discretion, a Member ID for your children any time you are logged on to the OLS. The Member ID will be used to recognize you and your children on the OLS portion of the K¹² Site. The Member ID will allow K¹² to recognize: your first and last name; registration ID; type of account, such as teacher, administrator, parent or student (if you created a separate Member ID and password for your children); school affiliation or the K¹² virtual program in which your children are enrolled; integration number; and the e-mail address you provided. The Member ID and the OLS will also allow you to track your children's attendance, school work and testing and to submit relevant portions of same to K¹², its affiliates and/or your local school to track your children's progress and abide by State and/or Federal standards and regulations.

K¹² calls customers to provide information they have requested and to answer questions. Because we only call customers at the telephone numbers they leave for us, K¹² does not call people by generating random or sequential telephone numbers. K¹² may use pre-recorded messages in order to ensure that customers receive the information they requested. Customers do not have to consent to receive calls in order to receive K¹²’s services.

K¹², its affiliates, and/or your local school may use personal information provided by you on your account information page on OLS to contact you about your children's progress, testing or attendance, customer service and quality control procedures. To the extent third party vendors assist K¹² and/or its affiliates in the provision of online products or services, those vendors are provided the minimum amount of data required to perform the tasks for which they have been engaged, have no independent rights to such data, and have agreed to adhere to the K¹² Privacy Policy.

K¹² may use the personal information on your account information page on OLS to provide you with information about new products and services available through K¹². You can request to opt out of receiving such information by making a request in writing to [privacy@K12.com](mailto:privacy@K12.com).

K¹² may share your information with companies that are not affiliated with K¹² but who are interested in sending you information about their products and services. You can request to opt out of the sharing of your personal information to independent third parties by making a request in writing to [privacy@K12.com](mailto:privacy@K12.com).

You can review, edit, and delete the personal information that you have provided to K¹² by making changes to your account information page on the OLS or making a request in writing to [privacy@K12.com](mailto:privacy@K12.com), as applicable. Please be advised that if your children are enrolled in a K¹² virtual program, the deletion of certain of your personal information may result in your children no longer being able to be enrolled in such program or utilize the OLS.

**Personal Information Provided by Parents About Children**

We understand that our student users who are under 13 years of age need special safeguards and privacy protection and it is our intent to fully comply with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA). K¹² does not collect personal information from children online at any point. K¹² only receives personal information about your children directly from you when you enroll your children into a K¹² virtual program. You can review any personal information that K¹² has regarding your children by reviewing your online account information page on the OLS and/or making such a request in writing to [privacy@K12.com](mailto:privacy@K12.com). You can request to opt out your children from the use of personal information by K¹², affiliates and vendors acting on behalf of K¹², by making a request in writing to [privacy@K12.com](mailto:privacy@K12.com). Please be aware that if you make such a request to opt your children personal information out of use by K¹², affiliates or vendors acting on behalf of K¹², your children can no longer continue to be enrolled in a K¹² virtual program or utilize the OLS. Therefore, a request by you for K¹², affiliates, and vendors acting on behalf of K¹² to no longer use your children's personal information will terminate your children's participation in the K¹² virtual program in which they are enrolled and their use of the OLS.

For information on COPPA and the use of children's personal information, please contact:

K12 Inc.  
2300 Corporate Park Drive  
Herndon, VA 20171  
888-968-7512  

**Message Boards and Chats**

We may offer K¹² message boards and chat rooms to you, the parent(s), on our Sites. Please be aware that anyone may read your postings on a message board or in a chat room. Furthermore, any information which you submit to be posted to a message board or in a chat room, including your information from your account information page and Member ID, will be disclosed and available to all users of that message board or chat room, and is therefore no longer private. We cannot guarantee the security of such information that you disclose or communicate online in public areas such as message boards and chat rooms, and you do so at your own risk. We reserve the right to monitor the content of the message boards only and to republish your postings from message boards or chat rooms elsewhere on the Web or otherwise in any format.

**Links**

The Sites may contain links to other websites, chat rooms or other resources that we provide for your convenience ("Linked Sites"). These sites are not under the control of K¹², and K¹² is not responsible for the content available on any Linked Site. Such links do not imply K¹²'s endorsement of material on any Linked Site and K¹² expressly disclaims all liability with regard to your access to such Linked Sites. Access to any other websites linked to the Sites is at your own risk.

**Our Commitment to Data Security**

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place commercially reasonable physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect. We also use Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) protocol on your account information pages to protect sensitive personal information.

**Changes in Corporate Structure**

If all or part of K12 Inc. or any of its affiliates are sold, merged or otherwise transferred to another entity the personal information you have provided at these Sites may be transferred as part of that transaction or process. However, K¹² will take steps to assure that the personal information is used in a manner consistent with the K¹² privacy policy under which it was collected. The Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act protects your children's educational records, in the event of such a transaction or transfer.

**Changes to the Privacy Policy**

We will occasionally amend this Privacy Policy to reflect company and customer feedback. We reserve the right to change, modify, add or remove portions of this policy at any time, and any changes will become effective immediately upon being posted unless we advise you otherwise. If you have any questions about K¹²'s privacy policy, please contact us in writing at [privacy@K12.com](mailto:privacy@K12.com).

Privacy Policy last updated April 23, 2013.

**Participation in the U.S.-E.U. and U.S.-Switzerland Safe Harbor Programs**

K¹² is a participant in the U.S.-E.U. and U.S.-Switzerland Safe Harbor programs developed by the U.S. Department of Commerce and the European Union and Switzerland. We have certified that we adhere to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles agreed upon by the U.S., the E.U. and Switzerland. For more information about the Safe Harbor and to view our certification, visit the [U.S. Department of Commerce's Safe Harbor](http://export.gov/safeharbor/) Web site. If you would like to contact K¹² directly about the Safe Harbor program, please send an e-mail to [legal@K12.com](mailto:legal@K12.com).

**K¹²  
CUSTOMER AND EMPLOYEE PRIVACY POLICY**

**EFFECTIVE DATE:   APRIL 23, 2013**

**I.           Purpose**

K12 Inc. ("K¹²," "we," "us" or "our") values the privacy of the parents, legal guardians and students whom we serve (collectively "Customers"), and of our Employees and job applicants.  This Privacy Policy (the "Policy") is designed to inform each Customer, Employee, and job applicant of K¹² and its affiliated companies and subsidiaries in Europe of:

(1) how his or her Personal Data (defined below) that is transferred to K¹² in the United States is processed, disclosed and transferred;

(2) his or her choices with regard to how such Personal Data will be used or disclosed by K¹²; and

(3) his or her other rights with regard to that Personal Data.

This Policy complies with the Safe Harbor Principles as agreed upon by the United States Department of Commerce and the European Commission.  Consistent with its commitment to protect personal privacy, K¹² adheres to these Safe Harbor Principles, which can be found at <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>.

All capitalized terms used in this Policy are defined at the end of this Policy.

**II.           Scope**

This Policy applies only to the processing of Personal Data that K¹² receives in the United States concerning its European Customers and Employees.

This Policy does not cover data from which individual persons cannot be identified, or situations in which pseudonyms are used (the use of pseudonyms involves the replacement of names or other identifiers with substitutes, so that identification of individual persons is not possible).

**III.           Collection and Use of Personal Data**

K¹² may receive Personal Data concerning Customers and Employees: (1) directly from the Customer or Employee, (2) from a European Affiliate or (3) through other means.

K¹² uses Employee Personal Data for business and employment purposes, including without limitation: (1) filling positions; (2) planning and implementing Employee transfers or assisting with Employee business-related travel; (3) managing employees from another country; (4) conducting performance evaluations and salary, bonus and equity reviews, and other Employee reviews; (5) administering payroll and benefits; (6) satisfying governmental reporting and tax requirements; (7) satisfying security, health and safety concerns; (8) planning and implementing potential acquisitions and mergers; (9) storing and processing data, including Personal Data, in computer databases and servers located in the United States; (10) implementing and maintaining K¹²'s information technology; (11) legal compliance; and (12) for other employment-related and business-related purposes permitted and/or required under applicable local law and regulation. If K¹² uses Employee Personal Data for any other purpose not listed in this Policy, K¹² will seek consent from the applicable Employee(s).

K¹² uses Customer Personal Data for business purposes, including without limitation:  (1) order and service fulfillment; (2) Customer service, including information technology support; (3) providing notices regarding services a Customer has purchased or may want to purchase in the future; (4) product or service improvement; (5) tailoring websites to provide a personalized Customer experience; (6) maintaining Customer records; (7) storing and processing data, including Personal Data, in computer databases and servers located in the United States; (8) implementing and maintaining K¹²'s information technology; (9) legal compliance; and (10) for other business-related purposes permitted and/or required under applicable local law and regulation. If K¹² uses Customer Personal Data for any other purpose not listed in this Policy, K¹² will seek consent from the applicable Customer(s).

**IV.           Disclosures/Onward Transfers of Personal Data**

K¹² discloses Employee and Customer Personal Data in limited circumstances and only to those who reasonably need to know such data for a legitimate business purpose and must abide by confidentiality obligations.  Absent consent of the Data Subject, K¹² will disclose Employee and Customer Personal Data only to third parties who perform tasks on K¹²'s behalf, and their contractors, provided that such third parties or contractors either: (1) comply with the Safe Harbor principles or use another mechanism permitted by the EU Data Protection Directive; or (2) agree to provide adequate protections for the Data Subject's privacy interests that are no less protective than those set out in this Policy and to use the Data Subject's Personal Data only for the purposes for which the third party has been engaged by K¹².  

K¹² may also disclose Employee and Customer Personal Data in response to a lawful legal process, as otherwise required by law, in the event of a sale of our company or assets of our company, and to protect or defend our rights or property.

**V.           Sensitive Data**

K¹² does not transfer Sensitive Data of Employees to the United States.      

K¹² transfers Sensitive Data of Customers to the United States in limited circumstances.  This Sensitive Data is limited to information regarding religious beliefs and physical or mental health or treatment, which is collected only for accreditation and teaching purposes.

**VI.           Confidentiality and Security of Personal Data**

K¹² maintains reasonable physical, administrative, and technical safeguards designed to secure Customers' and Employees' Personal Data, and to prevent unauthorized access to or unauthorized disclosure, alteration or destruction of such information. For more information about how K¹² protects its Customers' and Employees' Personal Data, please contact us via e-mail at: [legal@K12.com](mailto:legal@K12.com).  

**VII.           Right to Access, Change or Delete Personal Data**

Upon reasonable request and to the extent the request does not compromise the protections set forth in this Policy, K¹² allows Customers and Employees reasonable access to their Personal Data to correct, amend or delete such data.  Employees should direct any such request to their local Human Resources representative.  

If you are an Employee and you are unable to access, correct, amend or delete your Personal Data through your local Human Resources office, you may send a request to K¹²'s Legal Department.  All such requests must be sent by postal mail or by e-mail to the following address: Legal Department, K12 Inc., 2300 Corporate Park Drive, Herndon, VA 20171 or contact us via e-mail at: [legal@K12.com](mailto:legal@K12.com).

Customers should direct any such requests to Legal Department, K12 Inc., 2300 Corporate Park Drive, Herndon, VA 20171 or [legal@K12.com](mailto:legal@K12.com).

K¹² will endeavor to respond in a timely manner to all reasonable written requests to view, modify or delete Personal Data.

**VIII.           Data Integrity**

Customers and Employees are responsible for the accuracy of the data they provide to K¹².  K¹² will use reasonable efforts to maintain the accuracy and integrity of Personal Data and update it as appropriate. K¹² will not maintain Personal Data any longer than necessary for the purposes stated or as required by any applicable laws, unless otherwise agreed to by the Customer or Employee.

**IX.           Changes to this Policy**

This Policy is current as of the effective date set forth above.  K¹² reserves the right to change this Policy from time to time, consistent with applicable data protection and privacy laws and principles. Unless such changes afford greater protections to the privacy interests of Customers or Employees, or the affected Customers or Employees otherwise consent, such changes will apply only to Personal Data received after the effective date of such change. K¹² will notify Customers and Employees about material changes to the way it treats Personal Data by placing a prominent public notice on its website, [www.K12.com](http://www.k12.com/ "www.K12.com").

**X.           Questions or Complaints**

Customers and Employees may contact K¹² with questions or complaints concerning this Policy at:

Legal Department  
K12 Inc.  
2300 Corporate Park Drive  
Herndon, VA 20171  

**XI.           Enforcement and Dispute Resolution**

As part of K¹²'s annual certification process, K¹² will review K¹²'s compliance with this Policy.

If you are an Employee and have any questions, complaints, or disputes regarding the manner in which K¹² handles or protects your Personal Data, please bring it to the attention of your local Human Resources representative.  Complaints or disputes that cannot be remedied by your local Human Resources representative should be forwarded to the K¹² Legal Department at the address above.

If you are a Customer and have any questions, complaints, or disputes regarding the manner in which K¹² handles or protects your Personal Data, please bring it to the attention of the K¹² Legal Department at the address above.

With respect to any complaints regarding this Policy received from any Employee concerning EU Employee Personal Data that cannot be resolved through K¹²'s internal processes, K¹² agrees to cooperate and comply with the primary EU data protection authority for the data controller in question, and, where required, to take appropriate steps to address any adverse effects and assure future compliance.

With respect to any complaints regarding this Policy received from any Customer that cannot be resolved through K¹²'s internal process, K¹² agrees to participate in the dispute resolution procedures set forth by Judicial Arbitration and Mediation Services.  In the event that K¹² or Judicial Arbitration and Mediation Services concludes that K¹² did not comply with the Policy, K¹² will take appropriate steps to address any adverse effects and assure future compliance.

K¹² retains sole and absolute discretionary authority to resolve all questions relating to the administration, interpretation and application of this Policy. This authority includes construing the terms of this Policy, including any disputed or doubtful terms.

**XII.           Compliance**

Failure to comply with this Policy, undergo related training, and abide by all applicable privacy, data protection, and data security laws will amount to a serious disciplinary offence, subject to disciplinary measures which may include termination of employment.  
Any questions about the applicability or administration of this Policy should be immediately brought to the attention of K¹²'s Legal Department.

**XIII.           Defined Terms**

Capitalized terms in this Policy have the following meanings:

" **Customer** " means any parent, legal guardian or student that is a prospective, current, or past Customer of K¹² that stores personal data on equipment in the EU, the EEA, or Switzerland.

" **Data Subject** " means an identified or identifiable natural living person, and includes K¹² Customers and Employees. An identifiable person is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identification number or to one or more factors specific to his physical, psychological, mental, economic, cultural or social identity.

" **European Affiliate** " means a K¹² affiliate located in the EU, elsewhere in the EEA, or in Switzerland.

" **Employee** " means an employee (whether temporary, permanent, part-time or contract), former employee, independent contractor, or job applicant of K¹² or any of its affiliates, who is also a resident of the EU, another EEA member country, or Switzerland.

" **Personal Data** " means data that personally identifies a Data Subject or that may be used to personally identify a Data Subject (such as an identification number that identifies a Data Subject). Personal Data includes data such as an individual's name, address, phone number, e-mail address, user ID and password, and any other information that is combined with Personal Data (such as country of birth, marital status, emergency contact, salary information, performance information, terms of employment, and job qualifications (such as educational degrees earned). Personal Data does not include data that is unreadable or anonymized, or publicly available information that has not been combined with non-public Personal Data.

" **Sensitive Data** " means Personal Data that discloses a Data Subject's medical or health condition; race or ethnicity; criminal convictions; political, religious, or philosophical affiliations or opinions; sexual orientation; or trade union membership.
